when you think of some of the most
versatile pieces of gym equipment you
gotta include the kettlebell sorry y'all
i don't make the rules that's just how
it is
kettlebell workouts combine
explosiveness and endurance plus they're
gonna decrease the amount of stress your
body has to go under on it has some of
the most popular kettlebells on the
market so today
that's what i'm going to be breaking
down for you guys
what's up my people it's jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video i've got a kettlebell from on it
if you're looking for a review it's
gonna break down the price the features
some pros and cons as well as who should
or maybe should not purchase one of
these kettlebells
i'm on it but okay okay enough with all
that before i get started though i gotta
let you know
we've reviewed a lot of kettlebells on
barbin.com and if you want to browse our
best list just search barbind best
kettlebells and you can find out for
yourself which one is going to suit your
fitness goals the best
okay so let's talk about what i like
about these kettlebells so for starters
the construction that went into these on
it used gravity casting so just a quick
explanation they essentially took their
iron poured it into a mold kind of let
gravity do the rest of the work so
that's going to make sure the weight is
consistent all the way through and that
it is as precise
as it could be
the handle here nice and wide at the
base but it also has color coding makes
it super easy super simple just to grab
and go so you can get straight to
working out and there is a powder coat
on these kettlebells so
it's chip resistant now i know chips and
the paint's not going to change anything
when it comes to working out with a
kettlebell
but that could ruin the aesthetic we all
want our stuff to look nice right i mean
i know i do so that's nice that it is
chip resistant plus that texture
it's gonna give you a nice grip when
you're working out but it's not gonna be
too rough on your wrist forearm whatever
it may be it's not gonna be too rough on
your skin while you're working out
okay so with that being said i did
notice a few things that could be a bit
of an issue for some of y'all out there
starting with the weight so that's going
to range from 13 pounds up to 70 pounds
that might be plenty for a lot of y'all
watching
but if you need anything heavier or
maybe even lighter you're gonna have to
look elsewhere because you're just kind
of you know out of luck when it comes to
that here
these are also not competition
kettlebells so the size is going to
increase as you go up in weight so
if you're really big on wanting your
kettlebells to be uniform in size
regardless of their weight definitely go
get yourself some competition
kettlebells
and money is always an issue really with
anything in life it's really no
different here
these are not available in a full set
so
if you wanted to get all of these it's
best to do it at once it's gonna cost
you right around 450 bucks now compared
to some other companies that do offer
full sets in that same range these
really aren't that far off
but that's going to be the best way to
go about it
i would not recommend purchasing these
one at a time because that might make
you spend more money in the long run
than really you intended on doing and
plus with on it you have to spend 150
bucks to get free shipping so if you
don't spend that much money up front
then you know shipping is gonna add on
your total and that's where really you
could wind up spending more money in the
long run so i would definitely just
recommend saving up for a little bit and
getting these
all at once if that's what you plan on
doing
[Music]
okay so possibly the biggest question
that really everybody has with any
product is
how much money am i going to be spending
so let's talk about that once again you
cannot purchase these in a full set so
the cheapest option is going to be the
13-pound kettlebell it's right around 20
bucks this 26 pound kettlebell right
around 40
and that 70 pound bell is about 90 bucks
or so now shipping is gonna you know
increase that price and it's gonna vary
depending on how fast you want your
kettlebells
but if you spend 150 bucks you do get
free shipping so it might save you some
money in the long run something to think
about okay so once you really consider
the price of these kettlebells you're
getting a really good deal compared to
some of the other big name competitors
that are out there on the market they're
cheaper than those competitors but
they're also around the same price as
something you'd find at walmart or
target but i would have like to assume
that the quality here is much nicer than
what you're gonna get at one of those
stores so specifically comparing this to
a company like rogue you're going to
save about 30 to 40 bucks for each
individual kettlebell so price is
something that on it really has going
for them and that makes these a good
option in my eyes
okay so let's talk about the build now
with these on it kettlebells now
unfortunately i wasn't able to find the
exact dimensions when it comes to the
handle diameter but just to compare
some other 26 pound kettlebells i've
used in the past like this one
this handle seems pretty similar to
those probably right around an inch
maybe a little bit over an inch just
something worth remembering
they did use
gravity casting for these kettlebells so
once again it's going to be super
consistent with the weight all the way
through
it's really it's just going to be pretty
much as precise as possible for whatever
weight is advertised on
all of their kettlebells across the
board the handle does have nice color
coding right here just makes it super
easy to grab and go get straight to your
workout and you do have a nice wide base
down here so you can easily do any
two-handed style grips no problem at all
i like the powder coat gives me a pretty
good grip it's not gonna be too rough on
my skin and it's also chip resistant
which who doesn't like
[Music]
that all right so let's dig a little bit
deeper now into the features like i tend
to do
once again i wasn't able to find the
exact dimensions of the handle diameter
but like i said it seems to be right
around one inch maybe shade over it's
going to give you a really nice grip the
weight ranges from 13 pounds up to 70
pounds so like i said if you need
anything lighter you're not going to get
that here anything heavier well you're
not going to get it from on it in this
specific series but in their primal
series they actually do have a
kettlebell that goes up to 90 pounds so
maybe that's something you want to
consider anything other than that though
you have to look elsewhere
the handles do have nice color coding on
them it's just going to help you grab
and go get straight to working out but
also if you're just a little added
security blanket on the back there is an
engraving in both kilograms as well as
pounds just to make sure you know you're
going to get the right weight
it also has a nice flat base right here
there's no seam
makes it super easy to just set it down
it's really not going to wobble over or
fall over on you no matter where you're
storing it you know whether it be on a
shelf floor you're good to go and i
really like the powder coat makes it
look cool yeah but i like the texture it
brings it's also not going to be too
rough on my skin to give me that good
grip i want
and something i thought was really cool
i don't really see this advertised many
other places is that this is chip
resistant now for the sake of
our garage gym here i'm not going to put
that to the test and just start throwing
this around and see if any of the paint
chips maybe another day i'm not going to
do that today though so
i would like to assume that this is
going to stand up to the test
and not chip as you drop it
all right so let's do a quick walk
around with this kettlebell now let's
start with the fact you do have that
nice textured powder coat that i was
talking about it's chip resistant which
is pretty cool and so with the handle
it's a pretty good grip because of that
textured powder coat it's going to give
you a nice grip on its own but it also
mixes well with chalk if that's
something that you want to do now the
base of the handle is nice and wide
gives you plenty of space for both of
your hands to do those two-handed style
grips you often do with a kettlebell you
also have color coding right here on
each side of the handle that's going to
vary depending on which kettlebell
you're using but you know for right now
we've got the 26 pound bell
blue indicates it is in fact 26 pounds
now you have your on it engraving right
here on the front but on the back
just to you know help you out a little
bit in terms of making sure you're
getting the right weight you'll find the
weight to be engraved back here so 26
pounds you'll see 26 pounds on the back
as well as 12 kilograms now if i flip
this over on the side
that's a pretty wide and obviously flat
base i think it might be wider than a
lot of other kettlebells that i've used
in the past so i think it might actually
lead to more stability and you know
prevent
even more wobbling when you go to store
your kettlebells
okay so who should purchase these on it
kettlebells well if you're looking for a
super reliable set of kettlebells
i think you're gonna like the fact that
these were made from gravity casting
that weight is consistent all the way
through
a lot of times when kettlebells don't
use gravity casting you know that
weight's not going to be exact like
these are going to be so that's
something to think about plus you do
have a nice powder coat right here it's
going to add to that texture give you a
nice grip without being too rough on
your skin
plus they're chip resistant which is you
know just a little nice cherry on top
the relatively low price tag makes these
super appealing in my eyes y'all
they're
pretty much cheaper than every single
other major brand out there but you're
not going to sacrifice the quality
whatsoever i mean you can go to walmart
and you can find yourself a kettlebell
it's priced right around the same as
this
but why would you want to do that
because that's probably not going to
last you as long as this one will and i
personally like the fact that they're
not coated in rubber
a lot of times i feel like kettlebells
that do have a rubber coating
tend to have you know like a little
bubble maybe a seam on the base well
you're not getting that here nice and
flat
no seam
i think it's gonna make it sit sturdier
and be more stable whenever you go to
store it
okay so what about the people who might
not want these on their radar well
if you're looking for your kettlebells
to come in a full set i mean you just
don't get that here yeah you can go
purchase them all at once but
it's not guaranteed that one of them is
not going to be sold out and you know
you just you don't have the option of
getting them in a full set these are
also not competition kettlebells so if
you want your kettlebells to be the same
size regardless of the weight
you're not going to get that here so
just go get yourself some competition
kettlebells and if you're not working
out outside or you know in a gym with
some rubber floors like we have here you
might not be too crazy that these are
not coated in rubber because you
definitely increase your chances of
ruining your home floors and i highly
doubt that you want that
all right y'all that's all i have today
over the onick kettlebells
these are a really good option they're
super durable thanks to the cast iron
plus they're consistent with their
weight because of that gravity casting
and you have a nice powder coat on here
it's going to add to the texture give
you a good grip it's chip resistant
which is really cool plus it's not gonna
irritate your skin
too bad but my favorite thing about
these is that they're available at a
pretty affordable price compared to some
other big name competitors out there and
the fact that these are basically the
same quality as those other options
however
with these specific kettlebells if you
want anything over 70 pounds you're not
going to get it like this on it does
have a 90 pound option but it's in their
primal series so the features are a bit
different but anything other than that
you're just gonna have to look elsewhere
thanks for watching everybody i hope i
answered some questions that you might
have about these kettlebells or maybe
even answered some that you really
hadn't even thought of yet
as always keep your eyes peeled for my
next review but in the meantime why
don't you head over to barbin.com and
you can read more on these kettlebells
just search bar bend on it kettlebell
review and you can read over everything
we discussed here today
i'll see y'all next time